<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Kearney Liu's Home</title><link href="http://www.kearneyliu.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.kearneyliu.com/feeds/all-zh.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.kearneyliu.com/</id><updated>2013-09-30T00:00:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Deliverable &amp; Readable</title><link href="http://www.kearneyliu.com/pages/2013/09/30/deliverable-readable.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-30T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Kearney Liu</name></author><id>tag:www.kearneyliu.com,2013-09-30:pages/2013/09/30/deliverable-readable.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Deliverable &amp;amp; Readable&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I am invloved into a project with full of energy, so I have not updated my blog for one month. However, I achieved many experience about designing and making a software, such as &lt;strong&gt;deliverable&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;clean code&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deliverable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's so important that we should finish our tasks before the due day when we are working. We should not make any excuse to explain why we do not work it out.Therefore, it's a big question that how I arrange my schdule of the task I have to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of majoring in Natural Language Processing, I am responsible for the part of term extraction and normalization in a business intelligence project. At first, I design how to design a data structure and interface for ten days. But I only have four weeks, and it's such a huge system. Then I start to code. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I encountered a problem that the data structure of a variable was false in the last few days. My mentor told me that the deliverable is so significant, do not waste others' time. So I have to stay up to revise my code. Finally, I completed it in the last two days and succeeded submiting it on time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I should put the fuction of machine learning into the whole system, and the algorithm is so challenging to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Clean Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, we should make our code readable and clean. The code is not just read by the computer, but, in most of time, the code is read by co-workers. If someone spends too much time reading your code, he will be annoyed about your code and look upon down your coding ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a saying from Bjarne Stroustrup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love elegant and efficient code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also mentions the code needs to be logic and each function must be abstracted. In addition, how to name the function as well as the comments, commit logs are designed to be clean. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, I experienced the clean code a lot. Elegant code may help us improve the efficiency a lot. So we can save a lot of time of reading others' code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, I would make my best to make code cleaner in order to keep a good coding principle.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Project"></category></entry><entry><title>Some papers I read about Opinion Mining and Sentiment Analysis and my notes</title><link href="http://www.kearneyliu.com/pages/2013/08/19/some-papers-i-read-about-opinion-mining-and-sentiment-analysis-and-my-notes.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-19T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Kearney Liu</name></author><id>tag:www.kearneyliu.com,2013-08-19:pages/2013/08/19/some-papers-i-read-about-opinion-mining-and-sentiment-analysis-and-my-notes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My research interest is &lt;strong&gt;Opinion Mining and Sentiment Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;. These days I read a lot of papers. Here are some of them. Share with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sentiment Analysis of Twitter Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apoorv Agarwal, ACL 2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Main Approaches&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POS-specific prior polarity feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tree kernel to obviate the need for tedious feature engineering &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all, the author just care more about the polarity of English word(non-stop) and its POS features. Besides, he proposes two models compared with baseline(unigram), and proves his methods are greater than the baseline. However, I think there may be some improvements, for instance, to use Standford NLP implement and achieve more info about the tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Merging SenticNet and WordNet-Affect Emotion Lists for Sentiment Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Soujanya Porial, ICSP2012&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Main motivation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding new useful information to SenticNet entries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expanding WordNet-Affect emotion lists with the SenticNet concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Main approach&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For classification, the author used two kinds of features of the concepts &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISEAR data-based features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features based on similarity measures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper tells us how to expand a exiting sentiment lexicon to involve more words. The method he uses is excellent, and enlightens me how to expand the SenticNet lexicon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Semantic Sentiment Analysis of Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hassan Saif, Iswc2012&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Main Approach&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduce and implement a new set of semantic features for training a model for sentiment analysis of tweets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a new type of features for sentiment analysis, called semantic features, where for each entity in a tweet (e.g. iPhone, iPad, MacBook), the abstract concept that represents it will be added as a new feature (e.g. Apple product)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper, the author extracts each entity in a tweet, and make up the concept. But I think it may be too sparse, if some tweets does not involve these words, the results could not be good. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Sentiment Analysis"></category><category term="Twitter"></category><category term="Paper"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello, BLOG!</title><link href="http://www.kearneyliu.com/pages/2013/08/14/hello-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Kearney Liu</name></author><id>tag:www.kearneyliu.com,2013-08-14:pages/2013/08/14/hello-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my own blog and I will tell what I think to the world!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Hello"></category></entry></feed>