<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kearney Liu's Home</title><link>http://www.kearneyliu.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.kearneyliu.com/feeds/all.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><item><title>Some papers I read about Opinion Mining and Sentiment Analysis and my notes</title><link>http://www.kearneyliu.com/pages/2013/08/19/some-papers-i-read-about-opinion-mining-and-sentiment-analysis-and-my-notes.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My research interest is &lt;strong&gt;Opinion Mining and Sentiment Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;. These days I read a lot of papers. Here are some of them. Share with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sentiment Analysis of Twitter Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apoorv Agarwal, ACL 2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Main Approaches&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POS-specific prior polarity feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tree kernel to obviate the need for tedious feature engineering &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all, the author just care more about the polarity of English word(non-stop) and its POS features. Besides, he proposes two models compared with baseline(unigram), and proves his methods are greater than the baseline. However, I think there may be some improvements, for instance, to use Standford NLP implement and achieve more info about the tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Merging SenticNet and WordNet-Affect Emotion Lists for Sentiment Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Soujanya Porial, ICSP2012&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Main motivation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding new useful information to SenticNet entries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expanding WordNet-Affect emotion lists with the SenticNet concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Main approach&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For classification, the author used two kinds of features of the concepts &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISEAR data-based features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features based on similarity measures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper tells us how to expand a exiting sentiment lexicon to involve more words. The method he uses is excellent, and enlightens me how to expand the SenticNet lexicon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Semantic Sentiment Analysis of Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hassan Saif, Iswc2012&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Main Approach&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduce and implement a new set of semantic features for training a model for sentiment analysis of tweets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a new type of features for sentiment analysis, called semantic features, where for each entity in a tweet (e.g. iPhone, iPad, MacBook), the abstract concept that represents it will be added as a new feature (e.g. Apple product)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper, the author extracts each entity in a tweet, and make up the concept. But I think it may be too sparse, if some tweets does not involve these words, the results could not be good. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kearney Liu</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>tag:www.kearneyliu.com,2013-08-19:pages/2013/08/19/some-papers-i-read-about-opinion-mining-and-sentiment-analysis-and-my-notes.html</guid><category>Sentiment Analysis</category><category>Twitter</category><category>Paper</category></item><item><title>Hello, BLOG!</title><link>http://www.kearneyliu.com/pages/2013/08/14/hello-blog.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is my own blog and I will tell what I think to the world!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kearney Liu</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>tag:www.kearneyliu.com,2013-08-14:pages/2013/08/14/hello-blog.html</guid><category>Hello</category></item></channel></rss>